CONTACT

P: 206-595-1821

E: michelle.r.nygren@gmail.com
W: www.michellenygren.dev

GH: <u>@michellerenehey</u> LI: /in/michellenygren/

TECHNICAL SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript
- HTML5
- CSS3

ENVIRONMENTS, FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES

- React
- Node.js
- Express
- Redux

DATABASE

PostgreSQL

TESTING-SUITES

- Jest
- QUnit

TOOLS

- Github
- Supabase
- Postman
- Heroku
- Netlify

EDUCATION

ALCHEMY CODE LAB, 2022 6-month intensive full-stack software development bootcamp, 1000+ hours

SEATTLE CULINARY ACADEMY, 2016 1.5 year pastry arts program, Most Outstanding Student

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON, 2010 BA in Spanish Language & Literature, Magna Cum Laude

MICHELLE NYGREN

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

ABOUT

I am a hyper-focused full stack software engineer who is passionate about people. I enjoy creating beautiful, accessible, empathetic web experiences that center on user experience, and embrace a growth mindset in all I do. I am an intuitive problem solver, an engaging collaborator, and a meticulous developer.

PROJECTS

GEO TONE - SITE & GITHUB

React, CSS, PostgreSQL, Express, Reactronica, Tone.js, Framer Motion

- Full-stack interactive audio sequencer built for the desktop with an allremote team on a 9-day sprint. The app is built to inspire music-making, with fully responsive visual feedback for a user. User auth data is hashed and encrypted using JSON Web Tokens and Bcrypt, data is managed in SQL.
- I developed our team's user story, led team as project manager, fully built out and implemented the back-end logic, and spearheaded project design.

SELF-CARE BEAR - SITE & GITHUB

React, Supabase, HTML, CSS

- A dynamically rendered CRUD app, utilizing a RESTful API to help users build and develop their ideal morning routine. Built with an all-remote team on a 4day sprint.
- I designed detailed wireframes for project layout, and substantially contributed to project collaboration with significant commits in project logic, utilizing React components and custom hooks.

BYOBEE - SITE & GITHUB

React, Supabase, Netlify, CSS

- A dynamically rendered single-page app, utilizing Supabase storage and CRUD functionality to encourage community-building and observation in the bee-loving community. Built with an all-remote team on a 4-day sprint.
- I oversaw component management, and took lead on database design, utilizing foreign-key relationships to connect database storage.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PROGRAM MANAGER & INSTRUCTOR The Pantry | 2018-2021

- Managed extensive programming of community kitchen, teaching classes and planning events to build community through food.
- Launched virtual teaching platform during COVID, using technology to build connection and increase classes from 12 to 32 per week.

BAKER

Google at Bon Appetit | 2017-2018

• Lead bread baker at Google's Fremont campus in Seattle, exceeding expectations of culinary needs for upwards of 3,000 Google employees.

DIGITAL MARKETING & PR COORDINATOR Numi Organic Tea | 2014-2015

• Collaborated cross-departmentally to manage all digital projects and public relations of international tea company.